<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour In Suez</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navigation_drawer">NavigationDrawerActivity</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="about_suez_category">About Suez</string>
    <string name="hotel_category">Hotel</string>
    <string name="restaurant_category">Restaurant</string>
    <string name="tourism_category">Tourism</string>
    <string name="events_category">Events</string>
    <string name="shopping_category">Shopping</string>
    <string name="store_category">Store</string>
    <string name="hospital_category">Hospital</string>
    <string name="help_category">Help</string>

    <!-- About Suez -->
    <string name="topic_one">Early Islamic era</string>
    <string name="topic_one_explain">In the 7th century AD a town named \"Kolzum\" stood just north of the site of present-day Suez and served as eastern terminus of a canal built by Amr ibn al-\\\'Aslinking the Nile River and the Red Sea.\n Kolzum\\\'s trade fell following theclosure of the canal in 770 by the second Abbasid caliph al-Mansur to prevent his enemies in Arabia from accessing supplies from Egypt and the lands north of it.\n Nonetheless, the town benefited from the trade that remained between Egypt and Arabia.\nBy 780 al-Mansur\\\'s successor al-Mahdi restored part of the canal.\n The Qarmatians led by Hasan ibn Ahmad defeated a Fatimid army headed by Gawhar al-Siqilli at Kolzum in 971 and thereby captured the town.\n Following his defeat  in Cairo by al-Siqilli at the end of that year, Hasan and his forces retreated to Arabia via Kolzum.\n Suez was situated nearby and served as a source of drinking water for Kolzum according to Arab traveler al-Muqaddasi who visited in 986.\n The Ayyubid sultan of Egypt, Saladin, fortified both Kolzum and Suez in to defend Egypt\'s eastern frontier from Crusader raids by Raynald of  Chatillon.\n Between 1183-84, Raynald had ships stationed in the Red Sea to  prevent the Ayyubid garrison at Kolzum from accessing water.\n In response, Saladin\'s brother al-Adil had Husam ad-Din Lu\'lu build a naval fleet which sailed to the southern  port of Aidab to end Raynald\'s venture.\n By the 13th century it was recorded that Kolzum was in ruins as was Suez which had gradually replaced the former as a population center.\n According to Muslim historians al-Maqrizi and al-Idrisi, Kolzum had once been a prosperous town, until it was occupied and plundered by Bedouins.\n Arab geographer al-Dimashqi noted that Kolzum belonged to the Mamluk province of al-Karak at the time.</string>
    <string name="topic_two">Ottoman and Egyptian rule</string>
    <string name="topic_two_explain">To prevent Portuguese attacks against Egyptian coastal towns and the Red Sea port of Jeddah, Qansuh al-Ghawri the last Mamluk sultan ordered a 6,000-man force headed by Selman Reis to defend Suez in 1507, which in turn limited the Mamluk military\'s capabilities against the Ottomans in the Mediterranean sea.[6] Following the Ottoman\'s conquest of Egypt at the beginning of the 16th century, Suez became both a major naval and trading station. The Ottoman fleets at Suez were instrumental in disputing control with the Portuguese over Indian Ocean trade. German explorer Carsten Niebuhr noted that in the 18th century a 20-vessel fleet sailed annually from Suez to Jeddah—which served as the Islamic holy city of Mecca\'s port and Egypt\'s gateway for trade with India. However, by 1798, during Napoleonic invasion, Suez had devolved into an unimportant town. Fighting between the French and the British in 1800 left most of the town in ruins.[1] Its importance as a port increased after the Suez Canal opened in 1869.</string>
    <string name="topic_three">Modern era</string>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="restaurant_open">Open</string>
    <string name="restaurant_close">Close</string>
    <string name="topic_three_explain">The city was virtually destroyed during battles in the late 1960s and early 1970s between Egyptian and Israeli forces occupying the Sinai Peninsula. The town was deserted following the Six Day War in 1967. Reconstruction of Suez began soon after Egypt reopened the Suez Canal, following the October War with Israel. Suez was the first city to hold major protests against the government of Hosni Mubarak during the 2011 Egyptian revolution and was the scene of the first fatality of that uprising.[7] On account of this, it has been called the Sidi Bouzid of Egypt, recalling that small town\'s role in the 2010–2011 Tunisian revolution.[8]</string>
</resources>
